<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>Cosmic Skeptic</title>
	<subtitle>Know the darkside of humanity.</subtitle>
	<link href="https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://cosmicskeptic.github.io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why Advertisements are Insidious?</title>
		<published>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/blog/advertising-industry/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/blog/advertising-industry/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Advertisement has become unquitous in our society. They have proliferated more than virus. And sometime I wonder whether ads are dangerous or virus?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am not going to discuss about privacy etc. here I am just going to specify why ads is dangerous.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#x27;s explore some ads I collected.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;advertising&#x2F;1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ads&quot; title=&quot;Youtube Ads&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above image can be roughly be translated to &amp;quot;I take 3k usd per night if you want to meet please visit me&amp;quot;. Is this legal? May be. But is it sign of good society where children can also see such ads?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;advertising&#x2F;2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ads&quot; title=&quot;Youtube Ads&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above image says &amp;quot;Live Mobile Video Chat&amp;quot;. We know the what video chat this means. How is youtube supporting small business by posting such ads?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;advertising&#x2F;3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ads&quot; title=&quot;Youtube Ads&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting sexual thumbnail has become trend in youtube. Is it necessary? Really? Am I absurd to think such ads should never come?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;advertising&#x2F;4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ads&quot; title=&quot;Youtube Ads&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here it comes the forceful ads that you need to see for 5 or 10 secs. And guess what you can&#x27;t even skip it. So, youtube is supporting small business by showing women tities moving here and there. Will feminist speak about such issue?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;img&#x2F;advertising&#x2F;5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ads&quot; title=&quot;Youtube Ads&quot; width=&quot;600&quot;&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ahh Mark Zuckerberg seems to support small business by telling people like me &amp;quot;I am going to be Dad soon&amp;quot;. Thanks Mark Zuckerberg for helping tiny gaming companies. Millions of teenager were wondering how to be dad and with your help they are going to be dad soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;it-is-cherry-picking&quot;&gt;It is cherry picking?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, it is but small thing like these can have huge impact tbh.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-to-be-safe-from-ads&quot;&gt;How to be safe from Ads?&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disable facebook from your children phone and if they need to contact may be use safer option like Signal or Whatsapp (Not privacy friendly)?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For youtube disable the stock youtube app and Install youtube vanced.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are member from school I would recommend to ban social networking sites like Facebook and recommend signal. Please don&#x27;t distribute news via Facebook and perphabs provide education on how one should deal with content on internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Do captcha really work?</title>
		<published>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/blog/captchas-dont-solve-any-problem/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/blog/captchas-dont-solve-any-problem/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;TLDR:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Captcha doesn&#x27;t work against rich people&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Captcha exploits poor people&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Metashit, Facebookshit supports predators by allowing nonsense advertisements&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People who take captcha jobs usually earn no to less money and they learn nothing. It is net negative to people even if they were earning anything because it’s a futile task.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Captchas help bot because a bot can exploit these poor Indian&#x2F;Pakisthan&#x2F;Nepali workers.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The major reason predators can exploit is poor government policy (no punishment to these predators), poverty (If people were rich why would they need to work for $100?), lack of regulation in Facebook ads (Do government get money from Facebook ads?)?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are made to believe that captcha solves various problems like it prevents bots from the website? Is it true? Let’s see why I think Captchas are creating a black market and exploiting poor people in Asia.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, there are websites like 2Captchas that boast themselves to be the best captcha solver. They also think they are doing charity by giving $100 per month. After that these website comes to Asian country because most of these countries are impoverished nation and many people are seeking jobs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, the companies start doing mass advertising (Popular reason to hate Mr. Robotbuck who thinks he is doing a favor to small businesses) in Facebook. Facebook is the preferred platform because many people spend their time on Facebook especially in Asia. And they start putting ads like &amp;quot;Are you jobless? We are here to solve your issue. You just need to type for us&amp;quot;. Then, they start their skulduggery. They hire people but to get that job if they can pay initially. (How ridiculous is that? We do jobs to earn money but here people are ready to pay for this shitty job). They convince people that after paying they can earn money easily.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But when people start to do this job they realize its not typing job rather its captcha solving job. The 100wpm candidate starts to work hard because they think it is better than nothing (Something is better than nothing?) and they can at least earn money because they already have invested like $20 in getting entry to such job. They are also made to work hard because there is something called a leader board where they show people are solving 5k captchas per week.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a month they realize they have been duped and they aren&#x27;t going to get their money back. And some people reported that even if they are paid they get very few amounts like $100.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, these predators succesfully hornswoggled the poor Asian. Government is busy with corruption and there are no laws that protect their right. Meanwhile, some rich people are running bots and probably earning in thousands of dollars. Captcha just makes it harder for normal people that why humans can never purchase the hot item from supreme.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>One Advantage of Crypto?</title>
		<published>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/blog/crypto-advantage/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/blog/crypto-advantage/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;TLDR:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto helps to bypass government regulation so that poor people from Argentina from tumbling fiat currency. Bypassing regulation has deep implications like website like wikileaks are able to receive funds. People have way less power to keep government in check.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you agree or not crypto is objectively bad. It is due to various reasons like:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Environmental Concerns (BTC)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Electronic Waste&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ponzi Schemes&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too many cryptos with pump and dump strategy&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proliferation of meme coins like dogecoin&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Too volatile. If Elon farts expect coin price to increase by 20%?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many crypto have been hacked so is our funds really secure?&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many hackers, scammers etc. are infamous for using cryptos.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above reasons can intersect each other. Regarding point 1, many people argue another crypto-like Solana, dots, etc. which follow the proof of stake doesn&#x27;t consume that much energy. You are correct but if we look at coin market cap proof of work coins dominate by a wide margin and other crypto follow it. Also, most of the time such coins are used to convert into BTC.  And regarding the proof of stake, it is always like Rich gets richer which I seriously don&#x27;t like.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all of these disadvantages, it has one surprising benifit. It can&#x27;t be easily intervened by the government. In dystopian countries like Argentina where the government is infamous for taking ransom in name of the tax, crypto plays a vital role in citizen&#x27;s life. If you think I am being ridiculous here you might need to reconsider your reason after reading my critical reasons.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you live in the west you might have underestimated your privilege. You might dismiss the idea that crypto is not solving the average joe problem. And yes I agree with that cryptos are mostly useless in western society. But for countries like Argentina cryptos are boon for citizens. Crypto is Hobson’s choice because you are too poor to pay tax. For Argentinians, tax is a euphemism for citizen blood.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Questions:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is a band tape solution? It will make the country poorer?
Yes, it only solves today&#x27;s problem and is not a long-term solution. But at least they can live today (Am I sounding ridiculous to justify it)? Remember the government is full of scoundrels. The tentacles of corruption are so deep for an average one person can do nothing. Democracy has become a useless word. It was supposed to be a government of the people but now its a government of elites (Oligoarch?).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One man can&#x27;t do anything in Argentina. The government is simply too powerful and we already know the consequence of Arab Spring which was futile on its own. In Arab spring lot of hopes were made but what we got in return, a more authoritarian government?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing government structure is going to take a long time even if people want. But people need to survive today so here we are...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not use dollar instead of crypto?
Because the dollar isn&#x27;t that convenient. For dollars, you need bank accounts, etc. In Crypto, the currency exists in electronic format.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What happens if the internet goes down?
You don&#x27;t lay eggs in a single basket. You will always need some fiat currency for purchasing groceries. But entire internet going down is generally a rare case?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crypto is too volatile?
The currency of Argentina is more volatile than that. At least if you look at 10 year period crypto seems to be an increasing trend?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government can&#x27;t tighten regulation
They have said the same thing for drugs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Aaran Xu</title>
		<published>2021-04-01T08:50:45+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-01T08:50:45+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/authors/aaran-xu/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://cosmicskeptic.github.io/authors/aaran-xu/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Creator of &lt;strong&gt;AdiDoks&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;aaranxu&quot;&gt;@aaranxu&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
